costargroup.com 2016-05-15

# Privacy Policy

### 1\. Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

### 2\. Personal Information and Application of Privacy Policy

This privacy policy provides users of [www.costar.com](http://www.costar.com/ "Commercial Real Estate") (the “Site”) and services provided by CoStar Realty Information, Inc. and its affiliates (collectively, “CoStar” or “we” or “us”) with information about how CoStar collects, uses and discloses personal information. Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Our business customers should note that personal information does not include business contact information, such as your name, title, business address and business telephone number.

This Site and the Product contain links to other web sites operated by third parties. CoStar has no control over, and is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of such third party web sites and this Privacy Policy does not apply to those web sites. By clicking on third party links you expressly relieve CoStar from any and all liability arising from your use of such third party sites.

### 3\. The Information We Collect

a) Analytics

We may monitor your web site usage in order to identify trends, aggregate statistics, optimize your use of the web site and provide a safer environment for purchasing. Examples of the data we may collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login credentials, your computer connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system and platform, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) click stream to, through and from our websites (including date and time), your CoStar related preferences and the terms you searched for.

b) Direct Collection

In a few areas on our Site, we ask you to provide information that will enable us to verify whether you are entitled to access and use certain information, materials and services available from our Site, to enable us to enhance your site visit, to assist you with customer service or technical support issues, to follow up with you after your visit, or to otherwise support your customer relationship with CoStar. Providing such information is completely optional. However, failure to provide it may mean that you cannot access and use certain information, materials and services.

For example, we request information from you when you logon to certain areas of our Site, where you may be prompted to provide us with your Passcode information as a condition to gaining access to certain information, materials or services.

Further personal information will be collected and used by CoStar when you choose to take certain actions through our Site, including:

  * subscribe to a product information newsletter;

  * ask to be added to our mailing lists to receive information about our products or services;

  * register for a conference or webinar or notify us of a change of address;

  * place an order;

  * participate in a sweepstakes or other promotional offer; and

  * provide feedback in an online survey.

In each of these instances, we typically ask for your name, e-mail address, phone number, address, employment information, product preference information, as well as other similar information that is needed to register or subscribe you to services or offers. On occasion, we may ask for additional information to enable us to provide you with access to and use of certain information, materials and services. In the case of product information newsletters or direct or electronic mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" to these mailings at any time.

c) Phone calls

CoStar conducts product research using professional researchers conducting phone interviews of commercial real estate market participants and their agents. CoStar records telephone or other communications with CoStar representatives, including research, customer service and sales personnel, for training, quality assurance and archival purposes.

d) Payment Details

You may choose to provide valid payment information to make a purchase via our Site. Any transactional information provided by you will be used by us to process a transaction and may be used to process future transactions at your request. Your credit or debit card number, card holder name, start date, expiry date, issue number and related transaction information (such as delivery address) will be stored securely by CoStar and/or its agents and will be retained in order to facilitate and personalize future transactions with you.

e) Cookies

Some areas of this Site use and require that your computer accept "cookies." Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer to keep track of settings or data for a particular web site. Cookies make it possible and easier for you to access and use certain areas of this Site. If you have disabled cookies from within your browser, or if you are running third-party software that intercepts or deletes cookies, you may not be able to visit certain areas of the Site.

### 4\. Accuracy

CoStar will, as necessary, keep information accurate and complete based on the information provided to it. However, information contained in files that are dormant or have been closed will not be actively updated or maintained by CoStar.

If an individual believes that any of his or her personal information held by CoStar is not correct, that individual may request an update of that information by sending a written request to CoStar’s Privacy Officer: Jonathan Coleman, General Counsel, 1331 L Street NW, Washington, DC 20005

### 5\. How We Use Personal Information

CoStar uses your personal information only for specific purposes. The personal information you provide to us when using our Site, such as your name, postal or e-mail address or telephone number will be kept confidential and used to support your customer relationship with CoStar, and to notify you of special offers, updated information and new products and services from CoStar, to conduct research, or to provide offers from third parties that we think may be of interest to you. Agents or contractors of CoStar that are given access to your personal information are required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for CoStar.

CoStar may combine personal information collected at its Site with data provided by third-parties for the purposes of offering you products and services that CoStar believes would be of interest to you. If CoStar obtains information from third parties other than public sources, CoStar requires those third parties to confirm that they have complied with applicable law in the collection and use of that information.

Circumstances may arise where we are required to disclose your personal information to third parties for purposes other than to support your customer relationship with CoStar, such as in connection with a corporate divestiture or dissolution where we sell all or a portion of our business or assets (including our associated customer lists containing your personal information), or if disclosure is permitted or required by law (for example, in connection with judicial proceedings or governmental investigations). CoStar also reserves the right to disclose your personal information to identify possible violations of the Terms of Use or a separate License Agreement, to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities that may be violating your rights, our rights or the rights of others.

### 6\. Data Processing

CoStar’s global corporate affiliates assist us in supplying and providing services to our customers. In addition, CoStar retains subcontractors, agents, advisors and suppliers to assist us in our business. CoStar may permit its affiliates and third parties to access your personal information in order to assist us; however, these parties must keep your personal information confidential and must not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for CoStar.

CoStar may process and store your personal information in the United States of America. In addition, some of our service providers, agents and suppliers are located outside of Canada. Your personal information will also be subject to the laws of those jurisdictions, which may not provide the same level of protection as Canadian law.

### 7\. Consent

CoStar obtains your consent for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information for the purposes of providing you with products and services by you giving us your personal information for those purposes. We use an opt-out standard for communications with you about our products and services and other products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please contact us by e-mail to [mklionsky@costargroup.com](mailto:mklionsky@costargroup.com). In addition, you can select unsubscribe on any of our electronic email marketing communications to you. If you opt-out of marketing communications, CoStar will still contact you in connection with providing you with the products and services you have requested from us.

### 8\. Retention

CoStar retains personal information as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected and as required to comply with business and legal requirements. The length of time CoStar retains personal information varies and may extend beyond the end of the individual’s relationship with CoStar.

### 9\. Security

CoStar takes steps to protect the security of the personally identifiable information we collect, including, for example, physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards.

### 10\. No Data Regarding Children

Although the Site can technically be viewed by children, we do not knowingly request personally identifiable information from them nor does the Site publish content that is targeted to children. No information should be submitted to, or posted at, the Site by visitors under the age of 18.

### 11\. Accessing Your Personal Information

You may request access and corrections to your personal information. If you would like to access and make changes to information that you have provided to us in connection with your online account, please log-into your account and review and correct the information that you provided. If you would like assistance in accessing or correcting other information, please contact us at [support@costargroup.com](mailto:support@costar.com).

### 12\. Amendment of CoStar’s Practices and This Policy

CoStar will from time to time review and revise its privacy practices and this Privacy Policy. Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date of the revised Privacy Policy as well as to existing information held by CoStar. Please refer to CoStar’s website for the most current version of its Privacy Policy.

### 13\. Accountability

CoStar has appointed a Privacy Officer to investigate and respond to privacy issues and to be accountable for CoStar’s compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about access to your personal information held by CoStar or about CoStar’s collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, or if you wish to make a privacy-related complaint, you may contact CoStar’s Privacy Officer: Jonathan Coleman, General Counsel, by e-mail at [jcoleman@costargroup.com](mailto:jcoleman@costar.com) or by mail at 1331 L Street NW, Washington, DC 20005.
